<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Farm-Life on Winkky Farms</title>
    <link>https://winkkyfarms.com/categories/farm-life/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Farm-Life on Winkky Farms</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 30 Jun 2025 23:30:54 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://winkkyfarms.com/categories/farm-life/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Morning Chores: The Best Part of My Day</title>
      <link>https://winkkyfarms.com/posts/morning-chores/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Jun 2025 23:30:54 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>https://winkkyfarms.com/posts/morning-chores/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;530-am-and-all-is-well&#34;&gt;5:30 AM and All is Well&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The alarm goes off, but I&amp;rsquo;m already awake. Farm life does that to you - your body learns the rhythm of the land, the needs of the animals, the pull of responsibility that never sleeps.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I slip out of bed, trying not to wake Sarah (though she usually stirs anyway - twenty years of marriage to a farmer teaches you to sleep light). The coffee&amp;rsquo;s already programmed from last night. First cup goes in the travel mug, second cup stays warm for when I come back in.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Welcome to Winkky Farms</title>
      <link>https://winkkyfarms.com/posts/welcome-to-the-farm/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 Jun 2025 22:51:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>https://winkkyfarms.com/posts/welcome-to-the-farm/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Welcome to Winkky Farms, where generations of farming tradition meet modern sustainable practices.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Our family farm has been nurturing the land and feeding our community for decades. Here you&amp;rsquo;ll find stories from our fields, updates on our crops and livestock, and insights into the rhythms of farm life that mark each passing season.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;what-youll-find-here&#34;&gt;What You&amp;rsquo;ll Find Here&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;🌾 Crop Reports&lt;/strong&gt;: Updates on what we&amp;rsquo;re planting, growing, and harvesting throughout the year&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>WORKPRO Multitool Review: The Farm EDC That Outperforms Premium Brands</title>
      <link>https://winkkyfarms.com/posts/workpro-multitool-review/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Dec 2024 11:20:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>https://winkkyfarms.com/posts/workpro-multitool-review/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;the-multitool-that-changed-my-mind-about-budget-tools&#34;&gt;The Multitool That Changed My Mind About &amp;ldquo;Budget&amp;rdquo; Tools&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ll be honest - I was skeptical when I first picked up this &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.amazon.com/WORKPRO-Stainless-Multitool-Multipurpose-Activities/dp/B0CTMJCYT9?ref_=ast_sto_dp&amp;amp;th=1&#34;&gt;WORKPRO multitool&lt;/a&gt;. After years of carrying premium brands that cost 3-4 times as much, I didn&amp;rsquo;t expect much from a &amp;ldquo;budget&amp;rdquo; option.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Six months later, it&amp;rsquo;s clipped to my belt every single day, and my expensive Leatherman sits in the drawer. Here&amp;rsquo;s why this tool completely changed my perspective on what makes a great farm multitool.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>WORKPRO Garden Tool Set Review: Complete Kit for New and Experienced Gardeners</title>
      <link>https://winkkyfarms.com/posts/workpro-garden-tool-set-review/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Dec 2024 16:45:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>https://winkkyfarms.com/posts/workpro-garden-tool-set-review/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;the-tool-set-that-surprised-me&#34;&gt;The Tool Set That Surprised Me&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;When we started planning our gardening classes at Winkky Farms, I faced a dilemma: how do you equip 8-10 students with quality tools without breaking the budget? That&amp;rsquo;s when I discovered this &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.amazon.com/dp/B0DLZY829C?ref=ppx_yo2ov_dt_b_fed_asin_title&#34;&gt;WORKPRO garden tool set&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;After using multiple sets for our classes over the past year, and watching how they hold up to both beginner enthusiasm and experienced hands, I can give you the real story on whether this kit delivers.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>WORKPRO Pruning Shears Review: 18 Months of Daily Farm Use</title>
      <link>https://winkkyfarms.com/posts/workpro-pruning-shears-review/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Dec 2024 10:15:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>https://winkkyfarms.com/posts/workpro-pruning-shears-review/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;the-tool-thats-in-my-pocket-every-day&#34;&gt;The Tool That&amp;rsquo;s in My Pocket Every Day&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;If you spend any time around Winkky Farms, you&amp;rsquo;ll notice I always have a pair of pruning shears clipped to my belt or in my back pocket. After going through several brands over the years, I&amp;rsquo;ve been using these &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B0DMV6F4WL/ref=ewc_pr_img_1?smid=A3P56LYOG94570&amp;amp;psc=1&#34;&gt;WORKPRO pruning shears&lt;/a&gt; for the past 18 months, and they&amp;rsquo;ve become my go-to tool for daily farm tasks.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Here&amp;rsquo;s what I&amp;rsquo;ve learned after putting them through real-world farm use.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Gardzen 20-Gallon Grow Bags: A Farmers Honest Review After Two Seasons</title>
      <link>https://winkkyfarms.com/posts/gardzen-grow-bags-review/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Nov 2024 14:30:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>https://winkkyfarms.com/posts/gardzen-grow-bags-review/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;real-world-testing-two-seasons-with-gardzen-grow-bags&#34;&gt;Real-World Testing: Two Seasons with Gardzen Grow Bags&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;When we decided to expand our container growing operation for the farm stand, I needed something bigger than traditional pots but more flexible than permanent raised beds. That&amp;rsquo;s when I discovered these &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.amazon.com/Gardzen-20-Pack-Gallon-Aeration-Handles/dp/B07V7ZNP7J?ref_=ast_sto_dp&amp;amp;th=1&#34;&gt;Gardzen 20-gallon grow bags&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;After two full growing seasons here in Zone 6a, I can give you the real story on how they perform.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;what-we-grew&#34;&gt;What We Grew&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Over the past two years, we&amp;rsquo;ve tested these bags with:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Farmhouse Kitchen Renovation: Where Tradition Meets Function</title>
      <link>https://winkkyfarms.com/projects/kitchen-renovation/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 10 Aug 2024 14:30:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>https://winkkyfarms.com/projects/kitchen-renovation/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;the-heart-of-our-home-gets-a-makeover&#34;&gt;The Heart of Our Home Gets a Makeover&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;For thirty years, our kitchen has been the command center of Winkky Farms. It&amp;rsquo;s where we plan the day over morning coffee, where the kids do homework while I prep dinner, where we process the garden harvest, and where three generations gather for Sunday meals.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;But after three decades of farm life, it was time for an update.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;why-now&#34;&gt;Why Now?&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The decision wasn&amp;rsquo;t made lightly. Farm families don&amp;rsquo;t renovate on a whim - we make do, we repair, we adapt. But when the 1990s laminate countertops started peeling and the cabinet doors wouldn&amp;rsquo;t stay closed anymore, we knew it was time.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Raising Farm Kids: Lessons from the Barn to the Classroom</title>
      <link>https://winkkyfarms.com/posts/farm-kids/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Jul 2024 19:30:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>https://winkkyfarms.com/posts/farm-kids/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;growing-up-with-dirt-under-their-nails&#34;&gt;Growing Up with Dirt Under Their Nails&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Emma is 8 and Jake is 16, and they&amp;rsquo;re growing up in a world that&amp;rsquo;s very different from the one Bill and I knew as kids. But some things about farm life remain beautifully unchanged - the lessons, the values, and the connection to something bigger than yourself.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Here&amp;rsquo;s what it really means to raise kids on a farm in 2024.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;morning-responsibilities&#34;&gt;Morning Responsibilities&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Before most kids their age are even awake, our children have chores. Not because we&amp;rsquo;re mean parents, but because 23 head of cattle and 50 chickens don&amp;rsquo;t care that it&amp;rsquo;s Saturday morning or summer vacation.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Deck Repair: A Father-Son Summer Project</title>
      <link>https://winkkyfarms.com/projects/deck-repair/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Jun 2024 16:45:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>https://winkkyfarms.com/projects/deck-repair/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;when-just-a-few-boards-becomes-a-full-rebuild&#34;&gt;When &amp;ldquo;Just a Few Boards&amp;rdquo; Becomes a Full Rebuild&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;It started innocently enough. Sarah mentioned that a couple of deck boards were getting soft. &amp;ldquo;Just replace a few boards,&amp;rdquo; she said. &amp;ldquo;Shouldn&amp;rsquo;t take more than a weekend.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Three months later, we had essentially rebuilt the entire deck. Here&amp;rsquo;s how a simple repair project taught us about planning, patience, and the value of doing things right.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-discovery&#34;&gt;The Discovery&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;What we thought was a few bad boards turned out to be a much bigger problem. When we started pulling up the obviously damaged planks, we found:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Barn Electrical Upgrade: Bringing the 1950s into the 21st Century</title>
      <link>https://winkkyfarms.com/projects/electrical-upgrade/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Mar 2024 09:20:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>https://winkkyfarms.com/projects/electrical-upgrade/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;when-safety-meets-necessity&#34;&gt;When Safety Meets Necessity&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The barn that Great-Grandpa Joe built in 1952 has served us well for seven decades. But the electrical system he installed? That was becoming a serious safety concern.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;When our insurance inspector pointed out the fire hazards lurking in our wiring, we knew it was time for a complete electrical overhaul.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-wake-up-call&#34;&gt;The Wake-Up Call&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;It started with a routine insurance inspection. The agent took one look at our barn&amp;rsquo;s electrical system and said, &amp;ldquo;This needs to be updated before we can renew your policy.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Winter Planning: Dreaming and Scheming for the Year Ahead</title>
      <link>https://winkkyfarms.com/posts/winter-planning/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Jan 2024 08:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>https://winkkyfarms.com/posts/winter-planning/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;the-quiet-season&#34;&gt;The Quiet Season&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Snow covers the fields, the equipment sits idle in the shed, and the pace of farm life slows to something almost resembling normal. But don&amp;rsquo;t let the quiet fool you - winter is when some of our most important work happens.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This is planning season.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-kitchen-table-becomes-mission-control&#34;&gt;The Kitchen Table Becomes Mission Control&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Every January, our kitchen table disappears under a pile of seed catalogs, equipment brochures, soil test results, and last year&amp;rsquo;s records. This is where we plan the coming year, dream about improvements, and make the decisions that will shape our next growing season.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
